All right.
好的。
So just to set the scene very quickly let's imagine there are 30 to 40 people in a relatively small
所以只是为了快速设置场景让我们想象一个相对较小的地方有 30 到 40 人
place.
地方。
There's a little stage.
有一个小舞台。
I walk up on the stage I'm going to give my presentation about the value of travel.
我走上讲台，介绍旅行的价值。
No slides.
没有幻灯片。
I'm just gonna go through my outline.
我只是要通过我的大纲。
But I could have slides.
但我可以有幻灯片。
I probably would.
我可能会。
This were a real situation.
这是一个真实的情况。
OK.
好的。
So I walk up on stage just by show of hands who here thinks that travel is more than just a vacation.
所以我只是通过举手走上舞台，在这里他们认为旅行不仅仅是一个假期。
Who here.
谁来了。
OK so about half of you about half of you think that when you go on a trip you're getting more than
好的，所以大约一半的人认为，当你去旅行时，你得到的不仅仅是
just relaxation.
只是放松。
Today I want to talk about what I feel is the the actual value of travel and why traveling can really
今天我想谈谈我觉得旅行的真正价值以及为什么旅行真的可以
teach us new things open our minds and give us genuinely meaningful experiences.
教我们新事物打开我们的思想，给我们真正有意义的体验。
And the first thing really is is about where we get ideas.
真正的第一件事是关于我们从哪里获得想法。
Being exposed to new things is an extremely important part of travel.
接触新事物是旅行中极其重要的一部分。
Seeing things that you've never seen before.
看到你以前从未见过的东西。
But for example when I first went abroad I actually traveled to India.
但例如，当我第一次出国时，我实际上去了印度。
I'd never travel abroad before.
我以前从来没有出国旅行过。
And India is a very different country than the United States where I'm from.
印度是一个与我来自的美国截然不同的国家。
So I plan to study study yoga.
所以我打算学习学习瑜伽。
I went over to India and it was just so different the smells the sights the sounds the language everything
我去了印度，那里的气味、风景、语言、一切都如此不同
was just so different that it shocked me at first.
太不一样了，一开始让我很震惊。
I was in a state of shock but after a day or two when it started to become comfortable all those sites
我处于震惊状态，但一两天后，所有这些网站都开始变得舒服了
and smells and sounds began to get comfortable and I became curious about each one.
气味和声音开始变得舒适，我对每一个都感到好奇。
And by speaking to local people I was able to learn about what people thought and I learned that what
通过与当地人交谈，我能够了解人们的想法，并且我了解到
people thought was different than what I thought my opinions and their opinions were different and that
人们的想法与我的想法不同，我的观点和他们的观点不同，而且
I realized is the beautiful thing about being human that we're all different.
我意识到作为人类的美好之处在于我们都是不同的。
We have our own viewpoints and each viewpoint is unique and really interesting in its own way.
我们有自己的观点，每个观点都是独一无二的，并且以自己的方式非常有趣。
Now another important part for me about travel is experiencing food and of course when I was in India
现在对我来说旅行的另一个重要部分是体验食物，当然当我在印度的时候
I was able to explore a lot of different cuisines that I had never imagined before.
我能够探索许多我以前从未想象过的不同美食。
I cannot tell you how important it has been for me to be able to experience all of the different cuisines
我无法告诉你能够体验所有不同的美食对我来说有多重要
that I've tried in my life whether it's in China Thailand India other parts of Asia Europe Africa even.
无论是在中国、泰国、印度、亚洲、欧洲、非洲的其他地区，我都曾尝试过。
And now that I'm back in the U.S. and not really traveling so much that's become part of who I am because
现在我回到了美国，并没有真正去旅行，这已经成为我的一部分，因为
I've been opened up to the possibilities of cuisine and food.
我已经敞开心扉接受美食和食物的可能性。
Now I feel like I need it.
现在我觉得我需要它。
It's part of me.
它是我的一部分。
So I have to go out here.
所以我必须从这里出去。
I live in New York.
我住在纽约。
I have to go out every week and find Chinese food one day Ethiopian food the next Indian food the next
我每周都得出去吃中国菜 第二天埃塞俄比亚菜 下一个印度菜
Mexican food the next.
接下来是墨西哥菜。
It's part of me now.
它现在是我的一部分。
It's an it and it's an incredibly valuable part of myself.
这是一个它，它是我自己非常有价值的一部分。
Now beyond just gaining new insights into how other people think into other cultures really broadening
现在不仅仅是获得关于其他人如何看待其他文化的新见解，真正扩大
our minds whether it's religion or for example how people eat food exploring cuisine travel also gives
我们的思想无论是宗教还是例如人们如何吃食物探索美食旅行也给
us the opportunity to step out of the grind the daily routine and when we do that a couple of things
我们有机会摆脱日常生活的束缚，当我们这样做时，会做几件事
happen.
发生。
One is that we start to see our own routine differently.
一是我们开始以不同的方式看待自己的日常生活。
Whenever I travel somewhere and I'm gone for a while and I come back everything that I thought was boring
每当我在某个地方旅行，我走了一段时间，然后我又回来了我认为无聊的一切
more.
更多的。
For example I often travel to China when I come back.
例如，我回来后经常去中国旅行。
I think I'm in New York New York is cool little interesting food we have here all my cats are here my
我想我在纽约 纽约很酷 有趣的小食物 我们这里有我所有的猫都在这里 我的
cats are wonderful my wonderful wife is here.
猫太棒了，我的好妻子在这里。
This is all great but sometimes sometimes.
这一切都很好，但有时。
Before I leave when I've been doing the same thing day after day it can begin to lose appreciation for
在我离开之前，当我日复一日地做同样的事情时，它可能会开始失去对
that but also when you actually go somewhere else you're somewhere new or somewhere you've never been.
而且当你真的去别的地方时，你就是一个新的地方，或者你从未去过的地方。
That as I mentioned culture shock can immediately put you into another state of mind another frame of
正如我提到的文化冲击可以立即让你进入另一种心态另一种框架
mind.
头脑。
And that's where inspiration happens.
这就是灵感发生的地方。
I found many of my best ideas when I've been thrown into unexpected situations when something I didn't
当我陷入意想不到的情况时，我发现了许多我最好的想法
expect to happen happened.
期望发生的事情发生了。
And when you're traveling everything that happens is generally unexpected.
当你旅行时，发生的一切通常都是出乎意料的。
You might encounter someone new you might see a mountain and it's so beautiful that you get an idea
你可能会遇到一个新人你可能会看到一座山，它是如此美丽以至于你有一个想法
or you appreciate nature differently.
或者你以不同的方式欣赏自然。
It's getting out of the routine that often shocks us into new insights and new appreciation for the
它摆脱了经常让我们震惊的例行公事，让我们对
world around us.
我们周围的世界。
I think it's a beautiful thing and I think that's often where a lot of the value of travel is missed
我认为这是一件美好的事情，而且我认为这往往是很多旅行价值被错过的地方
and people don't really think about it when they are on a very relaxing vacation and they're sitting
当人们在一个非常放松的假期并且他们坐着时，他们并不会真正考虑它
by the pool doing nothing.
在游泳池旁无所事事。
There's nothing wrong with that but when you're when you're out of the routine and you're exploring
这并没有错，但是当您脱离常规并且正在探索时
you can see things differently.
你可以看到不同的东西。
And on top of both of those things.
在这两件事之上。
Just travelling and meeting people is extremely valuable in itself.
只是旅行和会见人本身就非常有价值。
At the very least travel is a fantastic way to build a global network.
至少旅行是建立全球网络的绝佳方式。
I mean think about it.
我想说的是，考虑一下。
If you meet people and make friends in countries around the world even in your own country different
如果您在世界各国认识人并结交朋友，即使在您自己的国家也不一样
places around your own country you're going to expand your network.
在您自己国家的地方，您将扩展您的网络。
And that doesn't mean you should take advantage of people but it means more possibilities open up for
这并不意味着你应该利用人，而是意味着更多的可能性为
you in the future.
未来的你。
So for example I went to Japan with my friend who I'd met on another trip living in Japan said to me
例如，我和我在日本的另一次旅行中认识的朋友对我说
Hey you're coming to Japan.
嘿，你来日本了。
Well you can just stay with me I'll take you around the city.
好吧，你可以留在我身边，我会带你在城市里转转。
So I stayed with that person for a week.
所以我和那个人待了一个星期。
He took me around the city.
他带我在城里转了一圈。
We had a lot of fun together.
我们在一起玩得很开心。
And then that same person came to visit me in my home stayed with me in my home and I took him around
然后那个人到我家来看我
my city.
我的城市。
And that kind of exchange is beautiful because you deepen relationships but you also then can get for
这种交流是美好的，因为你加深了关系，但你也可以得到
example a deeper look into the local area because they know it better.
例如更深入地了解当地，因为他们更了解当地。
If you're by yourself traveling well you know you can read a tour book but the person who lives there
如果你一个人旅行得很好，你知道你可以读一本旅游书，但住在那里的人
is is going to know much more about it.
将会更多地了解它。
The best places to eat the best places to visit the best places to have fun.
最好的吃饭的地方最好的地方参观最好的地方玩得开心。
They're going to do a lot more about the local place.
他们将对当地做更多的事情。
Now from personal experience I would recommend when you travel stay in places like bed and breakfasts
现在根据个人经验，我建议您旅行时住在住宿加早餐旅馆之类的地方
or maybe even hostels because you have the opportunity to meet other travelers and you might then have
甚至可能是旅馆，因为您有机会结识其他旅行者，然后您可能会
experiences that you never expected to have.
你从未想过会有的经历。
I once was staying at a hostel and met a couple of girls and they were kind of afraid to go out because
我曾经住在一家旅馆，遇到了几个女孩，她们有点害怕出去，因为
it was getting dark.
天开始黑了。
And I said Oh well I can I can go out with you.
我说哦，好吧，我可以和你出去。
And so they felt safe to go out with me.
所以他们觉得和我出去很安全。
And because of that we ended up having this crazy adventure the next day actually where we went to the
正因为如此，我们最终在第二天进行了这场疯狂的冒险，实际上我们去了
zoo and I would never have done that if I hadn't.
动物园，如果我没有，我永远不会这样做。
That very interesting experience I would have never had that experience had I not met them.
如果我没有遇到他们，我永远不会有那种非常有趣的经历。
I might have I don't know gone to a coffee shop and done some work.
我可能不知道去咖啡店做了一些工作。
It would have been very boring.
那会很无聊。
Right.
正确的。
So the unexpected things often come when we meet new people.
所以当我们结识新朋友时，往往会出现意想不到的事情。
Those new people can get us out of our shell.
那些新人可以让我们摆脱困境。
So the next time you're planning a trip don't book a five star hotel.
因此，下次您计划旅行时，请不要预订五星级酒店。
Don't stay by yourself and sit by the pool and read.
不要一个人呆在泳池边看书。
That's fine to do sometimes.
有时这样做很好。
Next time why don't you try to have an adventure go somewhere crazy stay at a weird bed and breakfast
下次你为什么不尝试冒险去一个疯狂的地方住在一个奇怪的床和早餐
make new friends do something you've never done.
让新朋友做一些你从未做过的事情。
Try new food.
尝试新食物。
You're going to have experiences that are going to stick with you for the rest of your life.
您将拥有将伴随您一生的经历。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
All right.
好的。
So we've covered how to give a presentation the dos and don'ts talked about how to engage and how to
所以我们已经介绍了如何进行演示
make a hook.
做一个钩子。
We've talked about how to make an outline very important.
我们已经讨论过如何使大纲变得非常重要。
And I've given you an example presentation that I did not prepare before that I gave directly from my
我给了你一个我之前没有准备的示例演示文稿，我直接从我的
outline as a test to see how good my outline was.
大纲作为测试，看看我的大纲有多好。
And you can do it too.
你也可以做到。
Doesn't have to be perfect.
不一定要完美。
Mine wasn't perfect but if you do this more and more and you get used to it it gets more and more comfortable.
我的并不完美，但是如果您越来越多地这样做并且习惯了它，它会变得越来越舒服。
So when you need to give a real presentation and you have two weeks to prepare it's going to be easy.
所以当你需要做一个真正的演示并且你有两周的准备时间时，它会很容易。
You can spend your time looking for cool pictures for your team instead of worrying about what to talk
您可以花时间为您的团队寻找漂亮的图片，而不必担心要说什么
about because the outline part is not that hard.
大约是因为大纲部分并不难。
So to practice this I'd like you to choose a topic like travel life lesson you've learned the value
所以要练习这个，我希望你选择一个主题，比如旅行生活课，你已经学到了价值
of choosing your major in university.
选择你的大学专业。
Then create an outline just like we did in this lesson and then give your presentation recorded or give
然后像我们在本课中所做的那样创建一个大纲，然后记录您的演示文稿或提供
your presentation to a friend and recorded listen to it again and get feedback from from your friend
您向朋友的演示并录制了再次聆听并从您的朋友那里获得反馈
or you can get a group of friends.
或者你可以结交一群朋友。
Even better practice this if you get good at this.
如果你擅长这一点，那就更好地练习。
Wow.
哇。
If you can get good at giving presentations and making outlines you are powerful.
如果你能擅长做演示和制作大纲，那么你就是强大的。
Good luck.
祝你好运。